

SENIOR FULL STACK SOFTWARE
FNGINEER

Details

Kaipengalath
Calicut, 673641
India

+91 8129 060 272

rafeequekhp134@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Indian

DATE OF BIRTH

30th July 1992

Links

Github

Stack Overflow

<u>Facebook</u>

Linked In

Skills

NodeJS

JavaScript

VueJS

ReactJS

ES6

AngularJS

PHP & its frameworks

HTML & CSS

PHP

Laravel

Codelgniter

Profile

Experienced software professional with 10 years of expertise, possessing a strong knowledge base in NodeJS, VueJS, ReactJS, JavaScript, PHP, Laravel, AWS, AngularJS, MongoDB, MySQL, and more.

Proven ability to manage challenging situations and work under pressure, consistently accomplishing assigned tasks within specified timelines.

Kept abreast of the latest industry technologies and enthusiastic about continuous learning.

Possesses excellent logical, analytical, and problem-solving skills, coupled with strong team collaboration abilities.

Relevant educational background and nearly 10 years of industry experience.

Eager to take on challenges and handle difficult tasks, coupled with the ability to effectively manage clients.

Solid understanding of the software development life cycle and proficiency in utilizing testing tools for software quality assurance.

Seeking full-time or freelance remote opportunities.

Employment History

Sr Software Consultant, Cairs Technology India Pvt Ltd, Cochin

SEPTEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

A product based company based in US. My role here is to discuss the requirements with the offshore team, plan, co-ordinate the team to work for it together, develop and make sure that the outcome meets the exact requirements.

Software Engineer, Sparksupport Infotech PVt Ltd, Cochin

APRIL 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2017

I used to deal with the customers directly here. My role included to get the requirements, understand them and execute them with the help of NodeJS and MongoDB. I used to work on UI JS frameworks also.

Software Developer, Mattek Consultancy Services, Cochin

SEPTEMBER 2015 - APRIL 2016

Developing the web applications from scratch to meet the client requirements.

Web Developer, Mentor Performance Rating Pvt Ltd, Calicut

MARCH 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2015

Developing the web applications from scratch/existing to meet the client requirements and ensure the quality of the application to deliver bug free products to the clients.

Jr Software Engineer, Zaliyo Technologies Pvt Ltd, Calicut

OCTOBER 2014 - MARCH 2015

Coding with various programming languages to built web applications from scratch to meet the client requirements.

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology, CMS College of Engineering, Namakkal

MongoDB

MySQL

GitHub

Amazon AWS

Team role and leading

HTML and CSS

Customer/Client Management

Server Management

Languages

English

Malayalam

Hindi

Arabic

Hobbies

Playing football
Listening music
Learning new technologies
Reading books
Watching cricket

2010 - 2014

Higher Secondary, GVHSS Kondotty

2010

SSLC, KMHS Kottakkal

2008

References

References available upon request

Major Projects

Parentfinder, NodeJS, VueJS

MARCH 2015

Parentfinder.com is the most comprehensive, hands-on adoption profile service. It gives parents looking to adopt a baby the professional guidance and profile creation services they need while offering adoption organizations a trusted partner.

I work in both front end and back end development. I get the requirements and divide the tasks between the subordinates including me.

We develop the REST APIs with NodeJS and the user interface with VueJS. The database is MongoDB.

Parentfinder Family Badge

This is a plugin which can be added to any web Parentfinder associated agency web page to list out their clients on their website. Thereby agencies can show their waiting adoptive families to their customers.

It was developed in Vuejs and RESTAPIs were done in NodeJS.

I used to manage and develop the whole product.

Child Management System

Child Management System is an another platform where the children to be adopted were managed and listed to the waiting families.

Here the agencies can add/manage the children, add their adoption details and market their profile on web platforms.

We now develop this system in NodeJS and VueJS. I manage back end, front end and the database.

My Adoption Portal, Revamping - NodeJS, VueJS

JUNE 2019

My Adoption Portal is a platform which supports the adopting/birth families, caseworkers, agencies or attorneys for the entire adoption services including profile creation, case studies, training, marketing the profiles, documentations, programs, financial guidelines etc.

We're now working on revamping the project into NodeJS and Vuejs to make it more scalable, reliable and faster.

I work both in front end and back end along with a team of 5 developers.

Child Connect, Revamping - Laravel to NodeJS

NOVEMBER 2016

Child Connect provides a safe, confidential and secure online place to save and share memories. Life books are available online and in print.

This was done in Laravel and currently migrating to NodeJS

The process of revamp is in progress with NodeJS and ReactJS. We 3 developers are working on it.

Farook Collage PG Admission, Laravel, VueJS

2015

The Farook College PG Admission portal provides the candidates to sign up, enter their personal and mark details to get an admission for the autonomous college graduate course.

It includes the support to the students, final processing of the marks to produce the rank list, and admission processes.

Role: Back end development - Laravel

MES College PG Admission, Laravel, VueJS

2015 - 2016

The MES College PG Admission portal provides the candidates to sign up, enter their personal and mark details to get an admission for the autonomous college graduate course.

It includes the support to the students, final processing of the marks to produce the rank list, and admission processes.

Role: Back end development - Laravel, Database Management

School Management System, Codelgniter

A school management system, which handles students, teachers and admins.

It is helpful for student register, attendance, exam management, marks management, timetable, class managements, divisions, subjects and so on.

Role: Backend and Front end developer, Handle the RDBMS.

Declaration

I hereby declare that the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge.